Guide to the Historic Photographs and Drawings Collection Photo.002
New York University Archives
- Series I: Oversized Photographs and Drawings
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Basketball 1909-1910, 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Football Team, n.d- circa 1910; 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Basketball Team 1947-1948, 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Football Team c. 1904, circa 1904; 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Football Team 1922, 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - Joseph Mandel, Faculty at NYU Camp Sebago Shooting Bow and Arrow, 10.5x14 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: some curling along edges, small tear along top edge Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - Joseph Mandel, Faculty at NYU Camp Sebago Shooting Bow and Arrow, 10.5x14 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: some curling along edges, small tear along top edge,m bends on corners Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - CampSebago1 NYU School of Education Group Photo at Camp Sebago, n.d.; 17x14 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 14x11.5 Mounting size: 17x14 Recto: severe discoloration, water stain(?) along mounting and part of photograph, white writing from negative, yellowing along edges of mounting, bottom left corner of photo and mounting is missing Verso: heavy surface dirt and discoloration, planar distorition, water stains (?), three writings in pencil, pieces of mounting missing Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU School of Education Building Fires at Camp Sebago, n.d.; mounted black and white photograph Mounting and photo are the same size General: pieces missing from corner and edges Recto: tears in photographs and mountings along edges, some surface dirt Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, writing in blue pencil Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - 1931 Basketball Game at Madison Square Garden- Columbia University vs. NYU- Photo reprint and enlargement, December 31, 1931; 17x13 black and white photograph Recto: small tear along bottom edge, marks in red pencil, white writing from negative, Verso: writing in pencil and black pen, slight planar distortion Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - 1931 Basketball Game at Madison Square Garden- Columbia University vs. NYU, December 31, 1931; 20x11.5 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: pieces of edge and corners missing Recto: white writing from negative Verso: stamps in brown ink, two writings in pencil, heavy surface dirt, dark brown marks (possibly fingerprints). Condition: Fair (Box 1)
  - 1934 Basketball Game- NYU vs. Notre Dame at Madison Square Garden, December 29, 1934; 20x11 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: multiple breaks, pieces missing from top left and right corners. Recto: writing in white writing from negative Verso:heavy surface dirt, faded stamps at top and bottom Condition: Poor (Box 1)
  - NYU Track Team c. 1902, circa 1902; 13.5x10 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: slight discoloration/fading Verso: heavy surface dirt, deposits from adhesive, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Track Team c.1904, circa 1904; 13.5x9.5 mounted black and white photograph Recto: black marks/scratches, flaking along edges, bottom left corner missing Verso: heavy surface dirt and discoloration, skinning Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Track Team, n.d.; 13.5x10.5 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: tiny tears along edges Verso: heavy surface dirt, dark brown marks (possibly finger prints) Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU 1927 Track Team- Middle Atlantic States Champions, 13.5x11 black and white photograph on fiber papers General: extremely brittle, multiple breaks, pieces missing from three corners Recto: black writing from negative Verso: heavy discoloration/surface dirt, brown marks (possibly from fingerprints), writing in pencil Condition: Poor (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Track Team c.1904, circa 1904; 19.5x15 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 14x11 Mounting size: 19.5x15 Recto: hole in photograph, breaks and flaking of mounting Verso: heavy surface dirt, dark discolorations, brown lines, writing in pencil, hole through photo and mounting Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Track Team 1902-1903, 20x16 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 13.5x10 Mounting size: 20x16 Recto: writing in black pen on mounting, scratches and marks on mountings, pieces missing from mounting along the edge, Verso: writing in pencil, writing in black pen, heavy discoloration, stains from water(?) Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - GymnasticsTeam1 1907 and Inter-Collegiate Champions 1907) 1906-1907, 20.5x16 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13.5x10 Mounting size: 20.5x16 Recto: extreme discoloration/yellowing, mounting and photo are broken into two pieces, water stain, flaking along edges Verso: writing in pencil, dark stains Condition: Poor (Box 1)
  - NYU Basketball Team 1919-1920 National Champions, 2 copies of this item exist: Copy 1: 13.5x10.5 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Mounting and Photo same size Recto: scratches and breaks, bottom left corner missing, writing in black from negative Verso: label adhered to mounting, discoloration from adhesive, heavy discoloration, breaks in mounting Condition: Fair Copy 2: Photo size: 13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 17.5x15 Recto: some surface dirt on mounting, bend at top left corner, writing in black writing from negative Verso: pressure adhesive, skinning of mounting Condition: Good (Box 1)
  - NYU Basketball Team 1919-1920 National Champions, 2 copies of this item exist: Copy 1: 13.5x10.5 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Mounting and Photo same size Recto: scratches and breaks, bottom left corner missing, writing in black from negative Verso: label adhered to mounting, discoloration from adhesive, heavy discoloration, breaks in mounting Condition: Fair Copy 2: Photo size: 13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 17.5x15 Recto: some surface dirt on mounting, bend at top left corner, writing in black writing from negative Verso: pressure adhesive, skinning of mounting Condition: Good (Box 1)
  - NYU Basketball Team, 1909-1910; 20x16 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 13.5x11 Mounting size: 20x16 General: multiple breaks, cracks, and pieces missing Recto: large break down left side, writing in white from negative, writing in black pen, discoloration/yellowing Verso: heavy surface dirt, skinning, breaks and cracks in mounting Condition: Poor (Box 1)
  - NYU Football Team n.d., 13x9.5 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Mounting and photo same size Recto: heavy discoloration and surface dirt, bottom right corner missing Verso: writing in pencil, heavy discoloration and surface dirt, stains from water (?), scratches Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Football Team 1922, 14x11 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: tears and small pieces missing from edges, yellowing Verso: surface dirt, black markes, writing in black pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Football Team c. 1904, circa 1904; 15x12 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 13.5x10 Mounting size: 15x12 Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, writing in black pen, brown stains, water marks(?) Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Football Team 1910, 15.5x12 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 15.5x12 Recto: severe yellowing/discoloration, surface dirt, corners of mounting broken off Verso: heavy surface dirt, deposits from adhesive Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - FootballTeam1 NYU Varsity Football Team 1897, 16.5x13.5 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 13x10 Mounting size: 16.5x13.5 Recto: severe scratches, white writing from negative, discoloration/yellowing Verso: heavy surface dirt, discoloration, writing in pencil, writing in pen, writing in blue pencil, water spots (?) Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Football Team(?), n.d.; 15.5x12.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 15.5x12.5 Recto: water stains and or deposits on photo and mounting, pieces missing from mounting, surface dirt, yellowing/discoloration of mounting Verso: heavy surface dirt, black marks, scratches Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - Lacrosse Team 1928 (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - Lacrosse Team, circa 1890 (Map-case 8, Drawer 9)
  - Jose de Capriles and Hugo Castello of NYU Fencing Team, 8x10 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: planar distortion/curling Recto: small tear on top edge Verso: yellowing/discoloration (from mounting?), stamp in black ink, pressure adhesive. Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - Hugo Castello and fencer of NYU Fencing Team, 8x10 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: paper and adhesive desposits (possible from the removal of mounting?) Verso: pressure adhesive, heavy surface dirt, brown spotting Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - Hugo Castello and NYU Fencing Team- left to right: N. Lerner, J. Archer, V. Butockares, H. Castello, J. Cagnina, D Shriner, 9.5x8 black and white photograph (silver gelatin?) Recto: mirroring, discoloration/silvering, heavy surface dirt Verso: yellowing/discoloration, small black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - Fencing Champion- Hugo Castello 1935 Intercollegiate Three-Weapon Champion with Coach Julio M. Castello and Captain Henry P. Stral, 14x11 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 10x8.5 Mounting size: 14x11 Recto: heavy surface dirt on mounting, Verso:skinning of mounting, sever discoloration, heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU Sabre Fencing Team 1935- Max Frank, Jordan Uttal, and Captain Henry P. Stral, 11x14 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 8x10 Mounting size: 11x14 Recto: tear in mounting, black marks on mounting Verso: severe discoloration, writing in blue pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU Fencing Team- Individual Intercollegiate Medalists 1932-1933, circa 1933; 12x11 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 10x8 Mounting size: 12z11 Recto: writing in black pen on mounting, bottom right corner of mounting missing, yellowing and surface dirt on mounting Verso: photo attached to mounting with pressure adhesive, yellowing/discoloration, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU Fencing Team- 1936 Intercollegiate Three-Weapon Champions, 14x13 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 10x8 Mounting size: 14x13 Recto: corners chipped from mounting, some yellowing of mounting Verso: severe yellowing/discoloration, 2 writings in pencil, photo attached to mounting with pressure adhesive, black pencil marks on mounting Condition: good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - Hugo Castello and NYU Fencing Team Members (?), 14x11 black and white photograph General: planar distortion Verso: black stamp, black marks, some surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU Faculty Dinner in honor of Dean E.J. Kilduff- June 3, 1936, 2 copies exist 20x12 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: curling/planar distortion Recto: some tearing/small pieces missing from edges Verso: two writings in pencil, severe discoloration, heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - Meehan Men of NYU Reunion Dinner November 26, 1948, 18x9 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: bends along left edge, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, brown stains Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU Faculty Club- 25 Year Dinner- April 29, 1937, 14x11 black and white photograph on fiber Recto: small tears and bends along edges Verso: heavy surface dirt, two stamps in purple ink, pressure adhesive repairing tear in top right corner Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU Class of 1911 Reunion- September 30, 1949, 18.5x12 black and white photograph Recto: large tears, breaks and bends, two writings in white ink from negative Verso: surface dirt, mark in purple pencil Condition: poor (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - Annual Dinner for NYU Engineering Alumni- February 11,1911, 20.5x11.5 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 19.5x11 Mounting size: 20.5x11.5 Recto: scratches and surface dirt on photograph, flaking along edges of mounting, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, stamp in black ink Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU University Heights Faculty Club Dinner- April 29, 1937, 14.5x11 black and white photograph General: key and labeling included with photograph Recto: breaks and tears attempted to be repaired using clear pressure adhesive, muliple tears and breaks Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, breaks and tears attempted to be repaired using clear pressure adhesive Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - Testimonial Dinner for NYU Faculty Members with 25 Years of Service- March 22, 1952, 18.5x10 black and white photograph General: key and labeling included with photograph Recto: some yellowing along border, small bends along edges Verso: heavy surface dirt and some yellow stains Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU Varsity Baseball Team 1899, 16x13 mounted black and white photograph (silver gelatin print?) Photo size: 13x10 Mounting size: 16x13 Recto: scratches on photograph, deposits from adhesive and mounting, writing in silver pen, writing in pencil, bottom corners missing from mounting Verso: writing in pencil, writing in pen, heavy surface dirt, corners missing from mounting Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU Baseball Team 1920, 17x14 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 15.5x12.5 Mounting size: 17x14 Recto: writing in black pen, writing in white from negative, mounting broken and missing pieces from edges and corners, heavy surface dirt, black marks on mounting and photograph, scratches on photograph Verso: black marks (possible fingerprints), heavy surface dirt, flaking of mounting, black lines Condition: Fair (although mounting should probably be removed) (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU Baseball Team 1924-1925, 16x13 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 12x9 Mounting size: 16x13 Recto: writing in black pen, mounting broken and missing pieces from edges and corners, heavy surface dirt, black marks on mounting and photograph, scratches on photograph Verso: black marks (possible fingerprints), heavy surface dirt, flaking of mounting, black lines Condition: Fair (although mounting should probably be removed) (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - Dinner for Dean Hering of NYU- May 29, 1916, 10x8 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: white writing from negative, skinning along top edge Verso: writing in pencil, pressure adhesive, discoloration/yellowing Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - Dinner for Dean Hering of New York University- Hotel Manhattan May 29, 1916, 18x14 mounted black and white photograph 2 copies of this mounted image exist Photo size:13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 18x14 Recto: heavy surface dirt, writing in black pen, stamp in black ink, white writing from negative, bottom left corner of mounting bent Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, dark marks (possibly fingerprints) Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - Dinner for Professor John J. Stevenson of New York University- February 22, 1909, 18x12 mounted black and white photograph 3 copies of this item exist- 2 in good condition, 1 in fair General: planar distortion, tear in photo and mounting Recto: writing in white from negative, tear along right side, bottom right corner missing, breaks along edges Verso: writing in pen, scratches, flaking along edges, heavy surface dirt Condition: 2 Good and 1 Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 10)
  - NYU School of Education Alumni Luncheon- May 7, 1932, 20x12 black and white photograph General: planar distortion, curling Recto: black marks, curling, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, black marks, stamp in purple ink, red marks, curling Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU School of Education Alumni Association- April 4, 1936, 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: some surface dirt Verso: heavy surface dirt, stamp in purple ink Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU Commencement, University Heights, Alumni Group- 1914, 15.5x12.5 mounted black and white photograph General: planar distortion Photo size: 14x10 Mounting size: 15.5x12.5 Recto: some surface dirt Verso: two writing in pencils Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU Commencement, University Heights, Alumni Group- 1914, 15.5x12.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13x9.5 Mounting size: 15.5x12.5 Recto: dark stains, heavy surface dirt on mounting, embossing on mounting Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU Commencement, University Heights, Alumni Group- 1914, 15.5x12.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 12x13.5 Mounting size: 15x5x12.5 Genereal: planar distortion Recto: color distortion/silvering, some surface dirt Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - 40th Reunion of NYU Class of 1916- April 18, 1956, 17.5x10 black and white photograph General: break down the center of the photo (possibly from folding) Recto: writing in white from negative Verso: writing in pencil, some rippling along edges Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU Commerce Gridiron Dinner- June 2, 1937, 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist- 1 in good condition, 1 in fair Recto: break in center of photo (possibly from folding), writing in white ink from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, two writings in pencil Condition: 1 Fair, 1 Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - 20th Anniversary Dinner for NYU Commerce Class of 1917- January 16, 1937, 21x13.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 20.5x12 Rectowriting in white from negative, cracking along edges of photograph, surface dirt photo and mounting, crackling along surface of photo Verso: some surface dirt, deposit from adhesive, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - 10th Annual Reunion for NYU School of Commerce- Class of 1917- January 29, 1927, 20.5x13 mounted black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Photo size: 20x12 Mounting size: 20.5x13 Recto: heavy surface dirt along edges, white writing from negative, planar distortion, discoloration/yellowing Verso: heavy surface dirt, discoloration/yellowing, writing in pencil Condition: 1 Good and 1 poor (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - 40th Reunion of NYU School of Commerce- Class of 1917- January 17, 1957, 2 copies of this item exist- one mounted, one unmounted- both in good condition 22x14 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 20x12 Mounting size: 22x14 Recto: mark in pencil, some surface dirt, white writing from negative, planar distortion Verso: some surface dirt, discoloration/yellowing, deposits from adhesive, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Annual NYU Commerce Alumni Dinner May 7, 1936, 12x20 black and white photograph Recto: heavy surface dirt, curling/planar distortion Verso: heavy surface dirt, stamp in purple ink, black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - The Golden Anniversary Ceremonial Dinner- NYU School of Commerce- April 11, 1950, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some rippling along the edge Verso: surface dirt, strips of pressure adhesive, fingerprints Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU Student Body 1909 from 1910 Violet Yearbook, 1909-1910; 20x16 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13.5x10 Recto: yellowing/discoloration, heavy surface dirt Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Smoker Class of 1933 NYU Dinner- December 17, 1931, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: scratches, discoloration/yellowing, bottom left corner is missing, some breaks, chemical stains(?) Verso: writing in pencil, stamp in black ink, heavy surface dirt, dark brown stains, pressure adhesives Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Session of the Conference of Universities at the Waldorf Astoria- November 17, 1932, 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: stains (from chemicals?), curling and bends, rippling along edges Verso: writing in pencil, black marks, heavy surface dirt, yellow stains (from chemical?) Condition: 1 Fair and 1 Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Dinner in Commemoration of the Inauguration of Elmer Ellsworth Brown as Chancellor of NYU- November 9, 1911, 20x11.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 19.5x11.5 Mounting size: 20x11.5 Recto: some surface dirt, white writing from negative Verso: two writings in pencil, heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Dinner for Inauguration of E.E. Brown as NYU Chancelor- November 9, 1911, 20x11.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 19.5x11.5 Mounting size: 20x11.5 Recto: some surface dirt, bottom left corner missing, white writing from negative Verso: two writings in pencil, heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Dinner given by Dr. Albert Warren Ferris for NYU Classmates from Class of 1878- May 30, 1908, 17x12 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 17x11.5 Mounting size: 17x12 Recto: white writing from negative Verso: some surface dirt, two writings in pencil, stamp in black ink, writing in black pen Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU Club- Birthday Dinner in Honor of Kate S. Chittehden Given by the Alumni Association of the American Institute of Applied Music- April 17, 1936, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt, cracking on surface of photograph, tears along edges, writing in white from negative Verso: writing in pencil, stamp in black ink, pressure adhesive strips, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Alumni Association NYU Department of Arts and Sciences- February 9, 1909, 18x12 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 17.5x11.5 Mounting size: 18x12 Recto: white writing from negative, corners missing from mounting, small tears along edges of photo Verso: writing in pencil, surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU Class of 1907 Dinner, n.d.; 14x11 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 14x11 Recto: yellowing/discoloration, writing in white from negative Verso: three writings in pencil, heavy surface dirt, dark stains Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Testimonial Dinner in Honor of Henry Bailey Rathbone of NYU- April 25, 1941, 19.5x10.5 framed black and white photograph Recto: writing in white from negative Verso: not visible through frame Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)